A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, World Affairs, Series Q FA326
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Peace Plans
  - Peace Plans - Commission to Study the Bases of Peace - John Foster Dulles, May 1943-February 1948 (Box 26, Folder 223)
  - Peace Plans - Commission to Study the Bases of Peace - John Foster Dulles - Luncheon; March 18, 1943, 1941-1943 (Box 26, Folder 224)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. financed luncheon to introduce Dulles plan.
  - Peace Plans - Commission to Study the Bases of Peace - John Foster Dulles - Contributions, 1943-1948 (Box 26, Folder 225)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed $2,000-$5,000 1943-1948.
  - Peace Plans - Americans United for World Organization, Inc., 1944-1947 (Box 26, Folder 226)
    Worked for passage of United Nations Charter. Worked for World Government after 1945. No Rockefeller contributions. Raymond B. Fosdick, E. Hopkins, and Arthur W. Packard discuss relations between various "peace" agencies in America. Correspondents include E. M. Hopkins, Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard.
    110.15
  - Peace Plans - San Francisco Conference, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 227)
    Comments on Nelson A. Rockefeller's role. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    110.16
  - Peace Plans - San Francisco Conference - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Statement Regarding Prayer; April 4, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 228)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization
    Plans for United Nations. Suggestions for strengthening United Nations. Invitations. Pamphlets on United Nations. Family parties for delegates to United Nations. Housing for United Nations delegates. Extensions of United Nations ideas. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    110.17
    - September 1944-April 1949 (Box 26, Folder 229)
      David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 229A.
    - September 1944-April 1949 (Box 26, Folder 0229A)
    - May 1949-December 1950 (Box 26, Folder 230)
      David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 230A.
    - May 1949-December 1950 (Box 26, Folder 0230A)
    - January 1959-August 1953 (Box 27, Folder 231)
      David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 231A.
    - January 1959-August 1953 (Box 27, Folder 0231A)
    - September 1953-December 1954 (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - January 1955-December 1956 (Box 27, Folder 233)
      David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 233A.
    - January 1955-December 1956 (Box 27, Folder 0233A)
    - January 1957-November 1961 (Box 27, Folder 234)
      David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 234A.
    - January 1957-November 1961 (Box 27, Folder 0234A)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Contributions, 1946-1947 (Box 27, Folder 235)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $5,000 for Flushing site.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Rockefeller Family Dinner, Rainbow Room, 1950-1951 (Box 27, Folder 236)
    For heads of delegations to the General Assembly. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. stood expenses.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - UNO Site, January 1945-July 1947 (Box 27, Folder 237)
    Search for permanent site. Westchester location considered. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to cost of search. Tax questions.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also Box 48, Folder 434.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - UNO Site, August 1947-June 1948 (Box 27, Folder 238)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Offer, Miscellaneous Suggestions (A-L), 1946-1956 (Box 28, Folder 239)
    A variety of suggestions for location, construction and landscaping of United Nations buildings. Rockefeller office acknowledged most of them, pointed out that John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s participation ended with gift of land.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Offer, Miscellaneous Suggestions (M-O), 1946-1956 (Box 28, Folder 240)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Offer, Miscellaneous Suggestions (P-Z), 1946-1956 (Box 28, Folder 241)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Offer, December 10, 1946, 1946-1957 (Box 28, Folder 242)
    Letters of appreciation of gift from United Nations delegates and staff. Breaking ground, laying cornerstone. Arrangement of tax laws. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Offer, December 10, 1946, 1948-1956 (Box 28, Folder 243)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Offer, December 10, 1946 - Letter of Gift, 1946-1956 (Box 28, Folder 244)
    Giving $8,500,000 to buy site for United Nations. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s recollection of transactions preceding gift. Letter of gift. Preparation of $8 1/2 million check. Display of check in Chase Money Museum. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Offer, Correspondence Regarding Approach, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 245)
    Unsuccessful attempt to plan approach to United Nations site. Discussed by city Board of Estimate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Zeckendorf.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Publicity Regarding Offer, 1946-1950; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 246)
    Articles from magazines and journals about gift. Includes newspaper clippings.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Publicity Regarding Offer, 1946-1950; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 247)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Publicity Regarding Offer - Clippings, 1946-1956 (Box 28, Folder 248)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Letters of Approval and Protest - Protest (A-Z), 1946-1947 (Box 28, Folder 249)
    Letters of protest suggesting better ways to use the money; against United Nations in principle.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Letters of Approval and Protest - Approval (A-E), 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 250)
    Letters approving John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Letters of Approval and Protest - Approval (F-J), 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 251)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Letters of Approval and Protest - Approval (K-N), 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 252)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Letters of Approval and Protest - Approval (O-R), 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 253)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Letters of Approval and Protest - Approval (S-Z), 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 254)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - Committee of the City of New York, 1946-1955 (Box 29, Folder 255)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Day and Week
    Changed to United States Committee for the United Nations. Competition and conflict (1949- ) between the private American Association for the United Nations (UN Week) and the semi-government United States Citizens Committee for UN Day, over funds, jurisdiction and program of the United States Citizens Committee. Rockefellers involved in both organizations as participants and major contributors; also involved in negotiations attempting settlement of the conflict; United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund (UNICEF); John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Malcolm W. Davis, Dana S. Creel, Morehead Patterson, Thomas J. Watson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Eleanor Roosevelt.
    - July 1947-December 1951 (Box 29, Folder 256)
    - July 1947-December 1951 (Box 29, Folder 0256A)
    - January 1952-October 1954 (Box 30, Folder 257)
    - January 1952-October 1954 (Box 30, Folder 0257A)
    - November 1954-January 1955 (Box 30, Folder 258)
    - November 1954-January 1955 (Box 30, Folder 0258A)
    - February 1955-June 1955 (Box 30, Folder 259)
    - February 1955-June 1955 (Box 30, Folder 0259A)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Day and Week - Tarrytown United Nations Week - Christmas Parties, 1947-1950 (Box 30, Folder 260)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declines membership. Request for contribution, pledge. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Day and Week - Tarrytown United Nations Week - Christmas Parties, 1947-1950 (Box 30, Folder 0260A)
  - Peace Plans - United States Committee for the United Nations, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 261)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's gift, 1956; 1956 he leaves the executive committee. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's gift in 1957. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, E. B. Sayer.
  - Peace Plans - United States Committee for the United Nations, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 0261A)
    Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Peace Plans - United States Committee for the United Nations, 1956-1960 (Box 30, Folder 262)
  - Peace Plans - United States Committee for the United Nations, 1956-1960 (Box 30, Folder 0262A)
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Day and Week - Meetings, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 263)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's attendance.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organizations - International Children's Emergency Fund (UNICEF), 1947-1961 (Box 31, Folder 264)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organizations - International Children's Emergency Fund (UNICEF), 1947-1961 (Box 31, Folder 264A)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted material.
  - Peace Plans - Committee for One Million, 1953-1955 (Box 31, Folder 265)
    Against the admission of Red China into the United Nations. No answer to routine letters; no support. Correspondents include Charles Edison, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Frank Jamieson, Dana S. Creel.
    110.171
  - Peace Plans - Committee for One Million, 1956-1961 (Box 31, Folder 266)
  - Peace Plans - Atomic Bomb - Energy
    Discussions of use of atomic power. Scientists' pleas against future use and testing of atomic bombs. Laurance S. Rockefeller's interest in practical measures for protection against radiation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    110.18
    - 1945-1947 (Box 31, Folder 267)
    - 1948-1956 (Box 31, Folder 268)
    - 1948-1956 (Box 31, Folder 0268A)
    - 1957-1961 (Box 31, Folder 269)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1961 (Box 31, Folder 0269A)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1961 (Box 31, Folder 0269B)
  - Peace Plans - Atomic Energy - Fund for Peaceful Development of Atomic Energy
    David Rockefeller served on Board of Fund. Nelson A. Rockefeller made contribution. John D. Rockefeller 3rd made 1957 contribution to cost of Japanese conference on use of atomic energy. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, D. McLean, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    - 1954-1957 (Box 32, Folder 270)
    - 1954-1957 (Box 32, Folder 0270A)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 32, Folder 271)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 32, Folder 0271A)
  - Peace Plans - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, 1946-1948 (Box 32, Folder 272)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller declines participation in discussion of methods to curb atomic bomb. Other appeals denied. Correspondents include Albert Einstein, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    110.181
  - Peace Plans - European Federation - Unity, 1948-1956 (Box 32, Folder 273)
    Discussion of possible federal union of European states. American committee encouraging that goal. No Rockefeller participation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    110.19
  - Peace Plans - European Federation - Unity, 1948-1956 (Box 32, Folder 0273A)
  - Peace Plans - Atlantic Union Committee, 1949-1959 (Box 32, Folder 274)
    To develop support for Atlantic Pact. All requests for participation declined. No interest shown. Arthur W. Packard, William L. Clayton, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    110.20
  - Peace Plans - United World Federation, Inc., 1947-1959 (Box 32, Folder 275)
    To promote United Nations to world power sufficient to prevent war. No interest shown. Correspondents include Cord Meyer, Jr., Dana S. Creel.
    110.21
  - Peace Plans - National Committee for Free Europe, 1949-1953 (Box 32, Folder 276)
    Committee to aid Europe in its fight against communism. Unofficial. Reports on Russian police methods; search for peace; supported Radio Free Europe. No family interest at this time shown in files. But there are indications of contributions in later files on this subject. List of contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    110.22
  - Peace Plans - National Committee for Free Europe, 1949-1953 (Box 32, Folder 0276A)
  - Peace Plans - National Committee for Free Europe, 1954-1958 (Box 32, Folder 277)
  - Peace Plans - National Committee for Free Europe, 1954-1958 (Box 32, Folder 0277A)
  - Peace Plans - National Committee for Free Europe - Free Europe University in Exile, 1951-1953 (Box 32, Folder 278)
    For students exiled from their country.
  - Peace Plans - National Committee for Free Europe - Free Europe University in Exile, 1951-1953 (Box 32, Folder 0278A)
  - Peace Plans - Crusade for Freedom
    110.221
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions regularly. Martha Baird Rockefeller's contribution.
    - 1950-1951 (Box 33, Folder 279)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 33, Folder 0279A)
      David Rockefeller made contributions regularly.
    - 1952-1957 (Box 33, Folder 280)
    - 1952-1957 (Box 33, Folder 280A)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 33, Folder 281)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 33, Folder 281A)
  - Peace Plans - Radio Free Europe, 1951-1959 (Box 33, Folder 282)
    No contributions. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gives information on Japan.
    110.222
  - Peace Plans - American Committee on United Europe, 1949-1951 (Box 33, Folder 283)
    Committee supporting a federal union of west European states. Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller and Laurance S. Rockefeller interested in committee; no action shown in this file. Discussion of possible plans for European unity. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
    110.23
  - Peace Plans - American Committee on United Europe, 1949-1951 (Box 33, Folder 0283A)
  - Peace Plans - American Committee on United Europe, 1952-1959 (Box 33, Folder 284)
  - Peace Plans - American Committee on United Europe, 1952-1959 (Box 33, Folder 0284A)
  - Peace Plans - Committee on the Present Danger, 1951-1952 (Box 33, Folder 285)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller interest in group formed to sway public opinion toward adequate defense program for United States. Contribution made. Interest ceased in 1952. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
    110.24
  - Peace Plans - Committee on the Present Danger, 1951-1952 (Box 33, Folder 0285A)
  - Peace Plans - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1953-1957 (Box 34, Folder 286)
    North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and related organizations. Invitations to dinners, some accepted. Nelson A. Rockefeller contribution to American Council on NATO. Comment by Charles Noyes. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Charles P. Noyes.
    110.25
  - Peace Plans - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1953-1957 (Box 34, Folder 0286A)
  - Peace Plans - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1958-1962 (Box 34, Folder 287)
  - Peace Plans - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1958-1962 (Box 34, Folder 0287A)
  - Peace Plans - League of Nations Association, Inc., 1932-1939 (Box 34, Folder 288)
    Supported study of peace programs, preparedness program, aid to Great Britain. Switched to support of United Nations. Its support for World Court appealed to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick.
    110.31
  - Peace Plans - League of Nations Association, Inc., 1940-1945 (Box 34, Folder 289)
  - Peace Plans - League of Nations Association, Inc. - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1929-1944 (Box 34, Folder 290)
  - Peace Plans - League of Nations Association, Inc. - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1931-1944 (Box 34, Folder 291)
  - Peace Plans - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1941-1943 (Box 34, Folder 292)
    Grew out of League of Nations Association. Its program an educational one emphasizing winning of the war and a moral peace. Endorsed armed forces for United Nations, 1949. Rockefeller interests watched development of program, some comments. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.
    110.32
  - Peace Plans - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1944-1950 (Box 34, Folder 293)
  - Peace Plans - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace - Contributions, 1942-1944 (Box 34, Folder 294)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Peace Plans - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace - Printed Material, 1941-1945 (Box 35, Folder 295)
  - Peace Plans - American Association for the United Nations
    Grew out of League of Nations Association. Arthur W. Packard discusses United Nations proposals of Dunbarton Oaks. Mr. Dulles' comments reported to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Discussed strengthening of United Nations. John D. Rockefeller 3rd declined to serve on subcommittee of Association. Budgetary problems of the Association. Conflict with the United States Committee for the United Nations (see UN Day and Week envelope). Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, David Rockefeller, Eleanor Roosevelt, Dana S. Creel, Clark M. Eichelberger, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    110.33
    - 1944-1947 (Box 35, Folder 296)
    - 1944-1947 (Box 35, Folder 0296A)
    - 1948-1951 (Box 35, Folder 297)
    - 1948-1951 (Box 35, Folder 0297A)
    - 1952-1954 (Box 35, Folder 298)
    - 1955-1961 (Box 35, Folder 299)
    - 1955-1961 (Box 35, Folder 0299A)
  - Peace Plans - American Association for the United Nations - Contributions, January 1945-May 1955 (Box 35, Folder 300)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Martha Baird Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Peace Plans - American Association for the United Nations - Contributions, June 1955-February 1961 (Box 35, Folder 301)
  - Peace Plans - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (Citizens for Victory), 1940-1944 (Box 36, Folder 302)
    Campaigned for aid to Allies. Switched to support of war effort (name changed). John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made small contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    110A
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes to ad supporting League of Nations. Avoids public endorsement of World Court or comments on war debts, pacifism, disarmament. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributes to Emergency Peace Campaign. Many letters from individuals offering special personal plans for peace, ranging from prayer to action. Thomas M. Debevoise writes a letter to the New York "Times", 1945. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    110P
    - 1919-1938 (Box 36, Folder 303)
    - 1939-1941 (Box 36, Folder 304)
    - 1942-1944 (Box 36, Folder 305)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 36, Folder 306)
    - 1947-1950 (Box 36, Folder 307)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 37, Folder 308)
    - 1953-1958 (Box 37, Folder 309)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 37, Folder 310)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 37, Folder 311)
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies - American Peace Society, 1910-1934 (Box 37, Folder 312)
    Founded in 1828, incorporated in 1848. Appeals to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined. Society considered conservative by Rockefeller advisors. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies - Brooks-Bright Foundation, 1926-1930 (Box 37, Folder 313)
    To promote Anglo-American friendship by exchanging students. Arthur W. Packard interested but did not recommend contributions. None made. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods.
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies - Samuel Colcord Educational Publicity, 1920-1933 (Box 37, Folder 314)
    Began as a protest of Republican party dropping League of Nations. Raymond B. Fosdick approved but suggested John D. Rockefeller, Jr. stay out as it was too controversial. Strive to outlaw war. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies - Public Action Committee, 1935-1938 (Box 37, Folder 315)
    People's lobby group, writing to Congress on how to keep out of war. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gave $250. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies - Report - A. W. Armour, 1927 (Box 37, Folder 316)
    Study of Peace organizations made for Raymond B. Fosdick in 1927. Correspondents include A. W. Armour, Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1927-1940 (Box 37, Folder 317)
    Women's organization, work symbolized by Jane Addams. No Rockefeller contribution although Raymond B. Fosdick did make one in 1932 for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
  - Peace Plans - Peace Agencies - Robert Lee Humber - World Federation, 1941-1945 (Box 37, Folder 318)
    Carolinian urges World Federation. Formerly connected with American Church in Paris. Resolution passed by North Carolina and New Jersey legislatures. Campaign in New York. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interested but refused to give assistance, or to give public endorsement to resolution. Resolution passed in New York. Correspondents include R. L. Humber, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Peace Plans - Peace Treaty (Missing), 1919-1922 (Box 38, Folder 319)
    Newspaper clippings, pamphlets on treaty of Versailles.
  - Peace Plans - Society for the Prevention of World War III, 1944-1948 (Box 38, Folder 320)
    Printed material.
    110P2
  - Peace Plans - New York State Citizens Council for a Durable Peace, 1945-1948 (Box 38, Folder 321)
    Appeal to Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Gift made, not recorded here. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    110P3
  - Peace Plans - Moral Rearmament Movement, 1939-1956 (Box 38, Folder 322)
    Dr. Frank Buchman's crusade for spiritual reawakening of world. Appeals to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd for contributions or endorsement all declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    110P4
  - Peace Plans - Moral Rearmament Movement, 1957-1961 (Box 38, Folder 323)
  - Peace Plans - People to People Program, 1957-1961 (Box 38, Folder 324)
    Attempt to implement Dwight. D. Eisenhower's proposal for closer personal contacts between world citizens. Both David Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller declined any participation. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller.
    110P5
  - Peace Plans - People to People Program, 1957-1961 (Box 38, Folder 0324A)
  - Peace Plans - People to People Program - People to People Sports Committee, 1958-1961 (Box 38, Folder 325)
    No interest.
  - Peace Plans - United Nations Organization - UNO Site, July 1947 (Box 48, Folder 434)
    Index # 110.17
    Report to the General Assembly of the United Nations by the Secretary General on the Permanent Headquarters of the United Nations.
- War Relief